<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surveillances on Bottom-Up Default Analysis</title>
    <link>/surveillance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Surveillances on Bottom-Up Default Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/surveillance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV Canada</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4canada2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4canada2016/</guid>
      <description>Economic and financial context From the Country Report document, Box 2:
 The banking system remains sound but exposure to the oil and gas sector will require higher provisions against expected losses (Figure 4 and Table 6). Canada’s banking system is dominated by six banks accounting for 93 percent of bank assets.2 These banks are among the most profitable in the world, averaging 16 percent return on equity. They have stepped up the pace of business lending in recent years, but household credit which grew by double digits in 2010–11 has slowed to 5 percent today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV Chile</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4ichile.2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4ichile.2016/</guid>
      <description>Economic and financial context From the Country Report document, Annex II on macrofinancial linkages:
 Risks are tilted to the downside. On the downside, an unexpected slowdown in China or setbacks from pending adjustments in Brazil could dampen exports and investment, and tighten financing conditions as investor risk aversion increases. Sustained uncertainty about U.S. domestic policies, a shift towards protectionism, and faster than expected tightening of monetary policy could dampen external demand while raising inflation as the peso depreciates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV Indonesia</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4indonesia2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4indonesia2016/</guid>
      <description>Economic and financial context From the Selected Issues document, chapter 2:
 While overall corporate sector risks in Indonesia appear manageable, some corporates are facing higher risks including exchange rate, refinancing, or default, with possible spillovers to the banking system. With a slowing economy and a weakened rupiah, corporate balance sheets are expected to provide smaller buffers against negative macroeconomic shocks going forward. This paper assesses corporate sector vulnerabilities. It first describes the current situation in the corporate sector, and then projects corporate default probabilities under different macroeconomic scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV UAE</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4uae2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4uae2016/</guid>
      <description>Economic and financial context From the Selected Issues document, chapter 2:
 The paper aims at analyzing the financial stability implications of lower oil prices and higher short-term interest rates for the UAE. The paper focuses on the effects of lower oil prices and higher short-term interest rates on liquidity and solvency. To capture its different dimensions,4 liquidity is described by three indicators: the inverse of the loan-to-deposit ratio, the interbank loans-to-interbank deposits ratio, and the liquid assets-to-customer deposits and short-term debt ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 WHD Regional Outlook</title>
      <link>/surveillance/regwhd2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/regwhd2016/</guid>
      <description>Economic and financial context From chapter 3:
 Companies thrive in a healthy economy, and thriving companies are good business for banks. The converse is, of course, also true. In this box, we assess the impact of changes in macroeconomic conditions on nonfinancial corporate solvency risk, and its implications for the banking sector in LA5 countries—Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico, and Peru. In particular, we estimate the potential effect on bank provisions and capital from an increase in corporate solvency risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 FSSA Japan</title>
      <link>/surveillance/fsapjapan2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/fsapjapan2017/</guid>
      <description>Economic and financial context From the Technical Note on systemic risk analysis and stress testing:
 PDs for certain exposure classes such as foreign sovereigns and institutions are calculated for so called “low default portfolios,” and thus macroeconomic variables are typically not very useful to model such defaults. Historical PDs data for the institutions exposure class show little correlation with macroeconomic developments in Japan or key foreign regions included in the macro forecast scenarios (Euro zone, United Kingdom, U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>