<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bottom-Up Default Analysis on Bottom-Up Default Analysis</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bottom-Up Default Analysis on Bottom-Up Default Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>  BuDA User Guide</title>
      <link>/publication/a_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/a_guide/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> NUS-RMI CRI Technical Report</title>
      <link>/publication/a_technicalmanual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/a_technicalmanual/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 July Course</title>
      <link>/talk/2017july/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2017july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>    Jin-Chuan Duan</title>
      <link>/team/ajinchuan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/ajinchuan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>   Weimin Miao</title>
      <link>/team/bweimin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/bweimin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Jorge A. Chan-Lau</title>
      <link>/team/cchanlau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/cchanlau/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Wei Sun</title>
      <link>/team/dweisun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/dweisun/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV Canada</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4canada2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4canada2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-and-financial-context&#34;&gt;Economic and financial context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Country Report document, Box 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightskyblue&#34;&gt;
The banking system remains sound but exposure to the oil and gas sector will
require higher provisions against expected losses (Figure 4 and Table 6). Canada’s banking
system is dominated by six banks accounting for 93 percent of bank assets.2 These banks
are among the most profitable in the world, averaging 16 percent return on equity. They
have stepped up the pace of business lending in recent years, but household credit which
grew by double digits in 2010–11 has slowed to 5 percent today. The expansion in business
credit and increase in non-interest income have offset declining interest income margins.
As a result, the big six banks have continued to build up capital, with their common equity
Tier 1 ratios rising above 10 percent, while non-performing loans (NPLs) remain below ½ percent. The banks’ mortgage book is also
secured by government guarantees on high risk mortgage loans (those with loan-to-value (LTV)
ratios above 80 percent) some of which are pooled to raise financing in the securitization market.
Insured mortgage loans account for 50 percent of banks’ mortgage loan portfolio. 
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightskyblue&#34;&gt;
In terms of these banks’ exposure to the oil and gas sector, credit quality has deteriorated since 2014. 
Oil companies’ stock prices have fallen by 35 percent, their operating margin has declined by almost 15 percentage points, 
and their &lt;font color=&#34;orange&#34;&gt;&gt;median probability of default&lt;/font&gt; has increased sharply (Box 2).
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/scr/2016/cr16146.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IMF Staff Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV Chile</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4ichile.2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4ichile.2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-and-financial-context&#34;&gt;Economic and financial context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Country Report document, Annex II on macrofinancial linkages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightskyblue&#34;&gt;
Risks are tilted to the downside. On
the downside, an unexpected slowdown in China or setbacks from pending adjustments in Brazil
could dampen exports and investment, and tighten financing conditions as investor risk aversion
increases. Sustained uncertainty about U.S. domestic policies, a shift towards protectionism, and
faster than expected tightening of monetary policy could dampen external demand while raising
inflation as the peso depreciates. Domestically, the recovery in confidence could be further delayed
by a drawn-out resolution of legal uncertainty embedded in the new labor bill.
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightskyblue&#34;&gt;
The impact of downside risks materializing could be amplified through macro-financial
linkages. Although balance sheets in key sectors appear to be healthy (Annex II.A), historically high
household debt (60 percent of GDP), high leverage among non-financial corporates, and strong
inter-sectoral balance-sheet linkages are sources of vulnerability (network chart). Among large
corporates, foreign currency debt is substantial (55 percent in 2016Q1), although long maturities,
a substantial share of FDI related debt, and financial and natural hedges are containing risks
from currency mismatches.
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightskyblue&#34;&gt;
Severe stress tests of corporate balance sheets, which substantially raise
default probabilities of externally exposed firms, show that credit losses would be substantial. Even
so, the banking sector would manage to absorb a rise in credit costs thanks to sufficient capital
buffers.
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imf.org/~/media/Websites/IMF/imported-full-text-pdf/external/pubs/ft/scr/2016/_cr16376.ashx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IMF Staff Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV Indonesia</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4indonesia2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4indonesia2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-and-financial-context&#34;&gt;Economic and financial context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Selected Issues document, chapter 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightblue&#34;&gt;
While overall corporate sector risks in Indonesia appear manageable, some corporates are facing
higher risks including exchange rate, refinancing, or default, with possible spillovers to the banking
system. With a slowing economy and a weakened rupiah, corporate balance sheets are expected to
provide smaller buffers against negative macroeconomic shocks going forward. This paper assesses
corporate sector vulnerabilities. It first describes the current situation in the corporate sector, and then
&lt;font color=&#34;orange&#34;&gt;projects corporate default probabilities under different macroeconomic scenarios.&lt;/font&gt; Results from the
scenario analyses suggest that if economic growth slows sharply and recovers only slowly, the default
probabilities of domestic firms could rise to levels comparable to those during the Global Financial
Crisis. While this is a low-probability scenario, policy makers should continue to closely monitor
vulnerabilities and step up effort to strengthen contingency plans.
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extended version of the Selected Issues Paper was published in the Nov. 2017 issues of &lt;em&gt;Asia-Pacific Financial Markets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/scr/2016/cr1682.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IMF Selected Issues document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/viewer?url=https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jchanlauimf/Publications/master/2017%20Assessing%20corporate%20vulnerabilities%20in%20Indonesia.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asia-Pacific Financial Markets article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Article IV UAE</title>
      <link>/surveillance/art4uae2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/art4uae2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-and-financial-context&#34;&gt;Economic and financial context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Selected Issues document, chapter 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightblue&#34;&gt;
The paper aims at analyzing the &lt;font color=&#34;orange&#34;&gt;financial stability implications of lower oil prices and
higher short-term interest rates for the UAE.&lt;/font&gt; The paper focuses on the effects of lower oil prices
and higher short-term interest rates on liquidity and solvency. To capture its different dimensions,4
liquidity is described by three indicators: the inverse of the loan-to-deposit ratio, the interbank
loans-to-interbank deposits ratio, and the liquid assets-to-customer deposits and short-term debt
ratio. Their determinants are analyzed with a view to assess the impact of lower oil prices, higher
short-term interest rates, and other bank-specific characteristics. &lt;font color=orange&gt;Solvency is proxied by probabilities
of default under adverse macroeconomic scenarios.&lt;/font&gt; They are obtained with a forward intensity
model, which is flexible enough to incorporate not only defaults but also exits of firms from mergers
and acquisitions. Finally, the paper provides policy recommendations to mitigate the adverse effects
of lower oil prices and higher short-term interest rates on the banking system.
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imf.org/~/media/Websites/IMF/imported-full-text-pdf/external/pubs/ft/scr/2016/_cr16266.ashx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IMF Selected Issues document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 WHD Regional Outlook</title>
      <link>/surveillance/regwhd2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/regwhd2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-and-financial-context&#34;&gt;Economic and financial context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From chapter 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightblue&#34;&gt;
Companies thrive in a healthy economy, and thriving companies are good business for banks. The converse is,
of course, also true. In this box, we assess the &lt;font color=&#34;orange&#34;&gt;impact of changes in macroeconomic conditions on nonfinancial
corporate solvency risk&lt;/font&gt;, and its implications for the banking sector in LA5 countries—Brazil, Chile,
Colombia, Mexico, and Peru. In particular, we estimate the potential effect on bank provisions and capital
from an increase in corporate solvency risk. Banks in LA5 countries have a sizable exposure to corporate
lending, ranging from 8 percent of GDP in Mexico to 35 percent of GDP in Chile.
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The companion working paper, &lt;em&gt;Bottom-Up Default Analysis of Corporate Solvency Risk: An Application to Latin America&lt;/em&gt;,
 presents the analysis in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/REO/WH/Issues/2017/01/07/~/media/Websites/IMF/imported-flagship-issues/external/pubs/ft/reo/2016/whd/eng/pdf/0416/_chap3pdf.ashx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Regional Economic Outlook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=345071025031103100096003093002065066073031089055030062103010001112028040053092031098030096100055013085120125120095112066119102126112109001012086089097018087003025011091096087117071&amp;amp;EXT=pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Working paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 FSSA Japan</title>
      <link>/surveillance/fsapjapan2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/surveillance/fsapjapan2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;economic-and-financial-context&#34;&gt;Economic and financial context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the  Technical Note on systemic risk analysis and stress testing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font color=&#34;lightblue&#34;&gt;
PDs for certain exposure classes such as foreign sovereigns and institutions
are calculated for so called “low default portfolios,” and thus macroeconomic variables are
typically not very useful to model such defaults. Historical PDs data for the institutions exposure
class show little correlation with macroeconomic developments in Japan or key foreign regions
included in the macro forecast scenarios (Euro zone, United Kingdom, U.S., Emerging Asia). To
overcome this problem, &lt;font color=&#34;orange&#34;&gt;an alternative approach was used: PDs for institution asset class were
forecasted using the BuDA methodology.&lt;/font&gt; This model projects one-year
PDs for up to five years using the same macroeconomic scenarios. In the baseline scenario, it was
assumed that PDs would remain constant. BuDA PDs behave very similarly to EDFs. The estimation
uses equity prices and risk free rates (3-month Japan Treasury bill rates) as regressors. Both
scenarios reveal similar outcomes: in the moderate adverse scenario, the increase in PDs is driven by
a decline in equity prices, negative risk free rates (this reduces banks profitability), and in the severe
adverse one by a decline in equity prices, a decline in GDP and a flattening of th
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extended version of the Selected Issues Paper was published in the Nov. 2017 issues of &lt;em&gt;Asia-Pacific Financial Markets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imf.org/~/media/Files/Publications/CR/2017/cr17285.ashx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technical Note&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imf.org/~/media/Files/Publications/CR/2017/cr17244.ashx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Financial Stability Assessment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Research Initiative Team</title>
      <link>/team/drmiteam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/drmiteam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress Testing with a Bottom-Up Corporate Default Prediction Model</title>
      <link>/publication/c_stresstesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/c_stresstesting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
